# Laxmidutta Dash (1) Featured

Senior Software Engineer seeking roles in Software Development, Application

Maintenance, IT Project Management, Requirement Analysis, Unit

Testing, Java, J2EE, SQL, Servlets, Spring, Hibernate, RESTFUL, Webservices, HTML, JavaScript, X



Current Designation: Senior Software Engineer Total Experience: 5 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Harman Connected Services Notice Period: Currently Serving Notice Period

Current Location: Pune Highest Degree:

Pref. Location: Pune,Bengaluru / Bangalore,Mumbai Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Senior Software Engineer, Tech Lead, Software Development, Application Maintenance, IT Project

Management, Requirement Analysis, Unit

Testing, Java, J2EE, SQL, Servlets, Spring, Hibernate, RESTFUL, Webservices, HTML, JavaScript, XML, JSON, Annual Stript, Spring, Hibernate, RESTFUL, Webservices, HTML, JavaScript, XML, JSON, Annual Stript, Spring, Hibernate, RESTFUL, Webservices, HTML, JavaScript, XML, JSON, Annual Stript, Annual Stript

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 19-Jan-21 Last Modified: 19-Jan-21

# **Summary**

Highly Motivated Software Engineer with 5 years of enriched experience in Core Java, J2EE, Hibernate and Spring framework. In-depth knowledge of development language such as Core Java and Advanced Java.

A quick learner and eager to learn new things.

A self-motivated team player like to work in a team & a target-based person.

Possess positive attitude as well as effective communication skills.

Excellent in troubleshooting, have analytical and organizational skills.

Can work in a fast-paced environment, Good team player and can work independently.

Strong technical background and excellent interpersonal skills with an ability to interact with individuals at all levels.

# **Work Experience**

Harman Connected Services as Senior Software Engineer

Apr 2018 to Till Date

Client: Varian Medical Systems PROJECT: Analytics Platform

Description

It is an oncology information system is a complete web-based solution for all aspects of oncology care for all patients. The main objective of this project is to create a data pipeline that acts like a PaaS service

for designing dashboard reports which helps hospital and administration staff to take better decisions for patient treatment.

Abstract

Analytics Platform is a cloud based PaaS service created by Varian to ingest HL7 data from multiple sources. It enables the customer to refer dashboards based on this data which would help them in a faster and precise decision making.

Role

Team Member (Software Engineer)

Responsibilities

#### Requirement analysis and Design

Identifying areas for modification in existing code and subsequently making these modifications

Fixing and improving existing software

Writing efficient code based on specifications

Troubleshoot, and upgrade existing software

Developing modules from scratch as per the requirement

**Environment** Language: Java

Technologies: Spring Boot, Rest API, Apache Kafka, MongoDB, Docker, JSON, XML.

Tool: JUNIT, Log4j, Maven. Database: SQL server Cloud: Microsoft Azure

IDE: Eclipse

Project Duration: Mar 2018 to till date.

Team Size: 15

## Amdocs as Software Engineer

Feb 2017 to Apr 2018

PROJECT: OMS (Order Management System)

#### Description

- The main objective of this project is to manage all the orders that come from different sales
- channels based on customer requirement. Order Management System provides an automated
- solution to manage the service order lifecycle and help to fulfill complex multi-play bundled 0
- orders quickly and accurately.

#### Abstract

- It is an application which is used to place an order of High-speed Internet Access, Voice on IP, 0
- DirecTV etc. with updated price plan and different offers.

#### Role:

Team Member (Developer)

#### Responsibilities:

- 1) Requirement analysis and Design
- 2) Implemented business logic
- Development of Change List. 3)
- **UAT** support 4)
- Environment Stabilization. 5)
- 6) Environment:
- 7) Language: Core Java, EJB
- 8) Database: Oracle
- Server: WebLogic Server
- 10) IDE: Eclipse
- 11) Project Duration: Feb 2017 to March 2018

Team Size: 80

## Next Education India Pvt. Ltd as Software Engineer

Aug 2015 to Feb 2017

Next Education creates ground breaking products for the education sector that make learning and Teaching easier and effective. They are having products such as Teach Next, Learn Next & School ERP which is used by teachers, students & school managements. Teach Next is a digital learning eco- system which makes the end to end

process of teaching and learning more engaging and easy.

#### **PROJECT**

#### **NextERP**

Next ERP is a simple, easy-to-use school administration system that helps schools to automate various critical operations like admissions, fee management, and communications from parents, managing student records, examination, and results management. The main feature of this product is advanced data security measures, including data encryption, access restrictions, audit logs and trails, firewalls, and intrusion detections Supports chain schools and multiple branches. Environment: Java, Hibernate, spring, SVN, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery and DWR (An AJAX framework), MySQL. Clients: More than 200 schools from all over the India. (BVB, MPS, St. Joseph, GRD Academy, Rockwell). Team Size: 30+ Developers/Engineers.

#### Responsibilities

- Involved in NextERP product development.
- A Proficient Team Player of Admission and Student module.
- Developed many pages of Admission module and Student Module.
- Also developed other modules like Staff, GPS and Transport etc.
- Responsible for handling Admission and Student module.
- Follow Software Development Life cycle. \* Unit testing after development.

## **Education**

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from Biju Pattanaik University Of technology, Odisha in 2013

PG: in 0

## **IT Skills**

| Skill Name                           | Version       | Last Used | Experience               |
|--------------------------------------|---------------|-----------|--------------------------|
| Java/J2EE, SQL                       | JDK 8,<br>10g | 2019      | 4 Year(s) 8 Month(s)     |
| Servlets, Java Server Pages          |               | 2017      | 1 Year(s) 6 Month(s)     |
| SPRING, HIBERNATE                    |               | 2019      | 4 Year(s) 8 Month(s)     |
| restful webservices                  |               | 2019      | 2 Year(s) 1 Month(s)     |
| HTML, Javascript, Jquery             |               | 2017      | 1 Year(s) 6 Month(s)     |
| Apache Tomcat 7, Weblogic            |               | 2018      | 2 Year(s) 6 Month(s)     |
| MYSQL, ORACLE                        |               | 2018      | 4 Year(s) 8 Month(s)     |
| JASPER REPORT                        |               | 2017      | 1 Year(s)                |
| WINDOWS                              | Windows<br>8  | 2019      | 4 Year(s) 8 Month(s)     |
| ECLIPSE, MyEclipse                   |               | 2019      | 4 Year(s) 8 Month(s)     |
| SQL Yog, Toad                        |               | 2017      | 1 Year(s) 11<br>Month(s) |
| MAVEN,JSTL, CSS                      | 3.6           | 2019      | 4 Year(s) 8 Month(s)     |
| SQL Yog, MySQL Workbench & Toad      |               |           |                          |
| Log4J, Maven, SVN, JUNIT, Git, Jira  |               |           |                          |
| Apache Kafka, Flyway, MongodB, JSON. |               |           |                          |

## Languages Known

| Language | Proficiency | Read | Write | Speak |  |
|----------|-------------|------|-------|-------|--|

| English | Expert |
|---------|--------|
| Hindi   | Expert |
| Oriya   | Expert |

## **Projects**

**Project Title: Analytics Platform Client: Varian Medical Systems** Nature of Employment: Full Time

**Duration: Apr 2018 - Till Date Project Location: PUNE** Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Team Size: 15 Role: Sr. Programmer

Skill Used: Java, Spring Boot, Web Services, Rest, JUnit, Maven, Log4J, GIT, Apache Kafka, MongoDB.

Role Description: Senior Software Engineer - Product Development

Project Details: It is an oncology information system is a complete web-based solution for all aspects of oncology care for all patients. The main objective of this project is to create a data pipeline that acts like a PaaS service for designing dashboard reports which helps hospital and administration staff to take better decisions for patient treatment.

Project Title: AT & T OMS(Order Management System)

Client: AT & T

Nature of Employment: Full Time **Duration: Feb 2017 - Mar 2018** Project Location: Pune, India Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Role: Sr. Programmer Team Size: 6

Skill Used: Core Java, Oracle

Role Description: Team Member(developer)

Project Details: It is an application which is used to place an order of High Speed Internet Access, Voice on IP,

DirecTv etc. with updated price plan and different offers.

**Project Title: NextERP** 

Client: More than 200 schools from all over the India. (BVB,MPS,St. Joseph, GRD Academy,Rockwell).

Nature of Employment: Full Time **Duration: Aug 2015 - Feb 2017** Project Location: Hyderabad, India Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

**Role: Programmer** Team Size: 5 Skill Used: Java, Hibernate, Spring, SVN, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, DWR

Role Description: Team Member(developer)

Project Details: Next ERP is a simple, easy-to-use school administration system that helps schools to automate various critical operations like admissions, fee management, and communications from parents, managing student records, examination, and results management. The main feature of this product is advanced data security measures, including data encryption, access restrictions, audit logs and trails, firewalls, and intrusion detections Supports chain schools and multiple branches.

Project Title: MyNacre(Trainee management system)

**Client: Nacre Software Services** Nature of Employment: Full Time **Duration: Apr 2015 - Jul 2015** Onsite / Offsite: Offsite **Project Location: Hyderabad** 

Role: Other Team Size: 30 Skill Used: Servlets, JSP, JDBC, HTML, CSS, Javascript, JQuery, Oracle.

Role Description: Studied the requirements, understood them and developed my functionality accordingly. Designed using SERVLETS, JSP, JDBC, HTML, CSS and JS. Performed coding part of Add Technology

module.Performed Test cases for the project.

Project Details: To store the trainees details and to show the activities and schedules

### **Affirmative Action**

### **Work Authorization**

Category: General Job Type: Permanent

Physically Challenged: No **Employment Status: Full time**